Anthony Lewis Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Annual File, 1949-2007 (Box II:1-843)
  - 1998
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., (2 folders)
    - Health
    - Human rights
    - "H" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:710)
    - Immigration
      - Cullado, Jesus
      - General
        - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
        - May-July, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:711)
        - Aug.-Dec., (3 folders)
    - Iran
    - Ireland
    - Italy (Box II:712)
      - General
      - Trip
    - "I-J" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy family
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Latin America
    - Law
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Massachusetts Historical Society, Boston, Mass.
    - Mexico
    - Middle East (Box II:713)
      - General, (5 folders)
      - Sarraj, Eyad El, (2 folders)
    - Morgan, Elizabeth, (1 folder) (Box II:714)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - New York Times
      - General
      - Staff
    - "N-O" miscellaneous
    - Politics, (2 folders)
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Race, (3 folders) (Box II:715)
    - Religion
    - Right
      - Political conservatism
      - Religious conservatism
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Schwartz, Bernard
    - Secrecy (Box II:716)
    - Speeches
      - Jan.-Mar., (7 folders)
      - Apr.-July, (7 folders) (Box II:717)
      - Aug.-Oct., (5 folders) (Box II:718)
      - Nov. 4-10, (3 folders)
      - Nov. 17-20, (2 folders) (Box II:719)
      - Dec.
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - Surroundings
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:720)
    - Television
    - Terrorism
    - Tibet
    - "T-W" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Yugoslavia
      - Crimes
      - General
        - Jan.-May, (3 folders)
        - June-Dec., (4 folders) (Box II:721)
    - "Y" miscellaneous
  - 1999
    - Africa
      - Rwanda
      - South Africa
        - General, (3 folders)
        - Mbeki, Thabo
        - Trip (Box II:722)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Bilbao, Spain, trip
    - Blumenthal, Sidney, (2 folders)
    - Book reviews
    - Brennan Center for Justice, New York, N.Y., (2 folders)
    - Bush, George W., (2 folders)
    - Bylines (Box II:723)
      - American Prospect, (3 folders)
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Race, (2 folders)
    - "B" miscellaneous (Box II:724)
    - Capital punishment
      - Death Penalty Conference, Chicago, Ill., (3 folders)
      - General, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:725)
    - Clinton, Bill
      - General
      - Impeachment
        - Congress
        - Constitution
        - Senate, (3 folders)
        - Trial, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:726)
      - Jones, Paula, (3 folders)
      - Lewinsky, Monica S.
      - Starr, Kenneth, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box II:727)
      - Udolf, Bruce L.
    - Clinton, Hillary Rodham
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - Congress
    - Council on Foreign Affairs (Box II:728)
    - Courts, (3 folders)
    - Crime, (2 folders)
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Drugs
    - "D" miscellaneous (Box II:729)
    - Economy
    - Education
    - Europe
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Free speech
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Great Britain
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Trip
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard Magazine (Box II:730)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Human rights
      - East Timor
      - General
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Immigration
      - Aaron, Deborah
      - Cases and columns, (4 folders)
      - Cole, David, (2 folders) (Box II:731)
      - General
        - Jan.-June, (6 folders)
        - July-Sept., (7 folders) (Box II:732)
        - Oct., (1 folder) (Box II:733)
        - Nov.-Dec., (4 folders)
      - Thompson, Baxter A.
    - "I-K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Law (Box II:734)
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Middle East
      - General, (7 folders)
      - Trip, (1 folder) (Box II:735)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times
      - General
      - Staff
    - "N-O" miscellaneous
    - Politics
    - Population
    - "P-Q" miscellaneous
    - Race, (2 folders)
    - Religion (Box II:736)
    - Right, political conservatism
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Secrecy
    - Speeches
      - Jan.
      - Feb. 11-19, (3 folders)
      - Feb. 25, (3 folders) (Box II:737)
      - Mar., (3 folders)
      - May 3-5, (2 folders)
      - May 12-20 (Box II:738)
      - June-Dec., (5 folders)
    - Supreme Court
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Rehnquist, William H. (Box II:739)
    - Surroundings
    - "S-W" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Yugoslavia
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr.-Sept., (8 folders) (Box II:740)
      - Oct.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box II:741)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
  - 2000
    - Africa
      - South Africa
        - General, (2 folders)
        - Law, (3 folders)
        - Trip, (3 folders) (Box II:742)
      - Zimbabwe, (3 folders)
    - Albright, Madeleine Korbel
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, (3 folders)
    - Austria
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Book reviews (Box II:743)
    - Boston Freedom Award, (2 folders)
    - Brennan Center for Justice, New York, N.Y., (2 folders)
    - Bush, George W.
      - Capital punishment, (3 folders)
      - Debates
      - General, (2 folders) (Box II:744)
      - Law
    - Bylines, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:745)
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - California
    - Capital punishment, (4 folders) (Box II:746)
    - Chayes, Abram, (3 folders)
    - Cheney, Richard B.
    - Congress
    - Clinton, Bill
      - General
      - Starr, Kenneth, (7 folders) (Box II:747)
    - Clinton, Hillary Rodham (Box II:748)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - Constitution
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Courts, (4 folders)
    - Crime
      - General, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box II:749)
      - Habaes corpus, (2 folders)
    - "C" miscellaneous (Box II:750)
    - Defense
      - General
      - Nuclear weapons
        - General
        - Lee, Wen Ho
    - Drugs, (4 folders)
    - "D" miscellaneous (Box II:751)
    - Economy
    - Education
    - Europe
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Forbes, Steve, (2 folders)
    - Ford, Gerald R.
    - Freud, Sigmund
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gore, Al
    - Gideon's Trumpet, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:752)
    - Great Britain
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Trip
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Magazine
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Hawaii, trip (Box II:753)
    - "H" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Immigration
      - Aaron, Deborah, (2 folders)
      - Asylum, (3 folders)
      - Baptiste, Armando
      - Barry, Maria
      - Bayo, Abdou
      - Boles, Sherol
      - Cerda, Ernesto (Box II:754)
      - Chea, Socheat
      - Citizens
      - Columns
      - Detain
      - Dorochina, Tatiana
      - Elizabeth Detention Center, Elizabeth, N.J.
      - Epstein, Judy
      - Flores, Ana
      - Gehis, Mary Anne
      - General
        - Jan.-Feb., (4 folders)
        - Mar., (1 folder) (Box II:755)
        - Apr.-Dec., (11 folders)
      - Haiti (Box II:756)
      - Hay, Emma Mendez de
      - Johnson, Jimmy
      - Kurds
      - Mkhizi, Patrick
      - Narine, Clive
      - Niloofar, Alikhani
      - Oregonian
      - Portland, Wash.
      - Rios, José Romero
      - Said, Hawa
      - Samadi, Mahnaz
      - Statute, (2 folders) (Box II:757)
      - Tafu, Victor
      - Youth
    - Italy, trip, (2 folders)
    - "I-J" miscellaneous
    - Kimberlin, Brett, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:758)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Lester of Herne Hill, Anthony Paul Lester, Baron, (3 folders)
    - "L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - McCain, John (Box II:759)
    - Middle East, (7 folders)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:760)
    - New York Times
      - General
      - Staff
    - Nieman Foundation
    - "N-O" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Politics
      - Election, (1 folder); (7 folders) (Box II:761)
      - General (Box II:762)
      - Nader, Ralph
      - Republican National Convention
    - "P-Q" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Race, (2 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Speeches
      - Jan., (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box II:763)
      - Feb., (3 folders)
      - Mar. (Box II:764)
      - Apr., (4 folders)
      - May, (2 folders) (Box II:765)
      - June-Sept., (4 folders)
      - Oct., (1 folder) (Box II:766)
      - Nov.-Dec., (4 folders)
      - Supreme Court, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:767)
      - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Terrorism, (2 folders)
      - "T" miscellaneous
      - War crimes court, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:768)
      - "W" miscellaneous
      - Yugoslavia, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:769)
      - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 2001
    - Africa
      - General
      - Rwanda
      - South Africa, trip
    - AIDS (disease), (3 folders)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - Ashcroft, John D., (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box II:770)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Book reviews
    - Brennan Center for Justice, New York, N.Y.
    - Bush, George W.
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Texas
    - Bylines, (2 folders) (Box II:771)
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Capital punishment, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:772)
    - China
    - Clinton, Bill, pardons
    - Congress
    - Courts, (3 folders)
    - Crime
    - "C" miscellaneous (Box II:773)
    - Defense
      - General
      - Nuclear weapons
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Economy
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Free speech, (3 folders)
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Great Britain
      - Election
      - General, (2 folders) (Box II:774)
      - Trips
    - "G-H" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Immigration
      - Al-Jailani, Ashraf
      - Boles, Sherol Ann
      - Burma
      - Caza, Catherine
      - Cole, David
      - Collignon, Daniele
      - General, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:775)
      - Jacques, Ricardo
      - Shaban, Louis
    - Italy, trip
    - "I-L" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Middle East
      - Americans for Peace Now
      - General, (7 folders) (Box II:776)
      - Trip, (4 folders) (Box II:777)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - New York Times, (2 folders)
    - "N-P" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Reno, Janet
    - Retirement, (8 folders); (7 folders) (Box II:778, Box II:779)
    - "R" miscellaneous (Box II:780)
    - Sex, (2 folders)
    - Speeches
      - Jan.-June, (6 folders)
      - July-Dec., (5 folders) (Box II:781)
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - Surroundings, (2 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:782)
    - Terrorism
      - Falwell, Jerry
      - General, (4 folders)
      - Great Britain
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - "U-Y" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:783)
  - 2002
    - Afghanistan, (2 folders)
    - Africa, South Africa, (2 folders)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - Australia, trip
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box II:784)
    - Book reviews, (2 folders)
    - Brennan Center for Justice, New York, N.Y.
    - Bush, George W., (2 folders)
    - Bylines
      - Boston Globe
      - Daedalus: Journal of American Academy of Arts and Sciences
      - General, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:785)
      - New York Review of Books
        - Iraq, (3 folders)
        - Middle East, (2 folders)
      - New York Times, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:786)
      - Shehadeh, Raja
      - Wiesner, Jerome B.
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - Capital punishment
    - Clinton, Bill
      - General
      - Starr, Kenneth
      - Whitewater Inquiry
    - Committee to Protect Journalists, (1 folder) (Box II:787)
    - Constitution
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Drugs
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Energy, (2 folders)
    - Europe
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Free speech
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gay rights
    - Gideon's Trumpet (Box II:788)
    - Great Britain
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Magazine
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Health
    - Holbrooke, Richard C.
    - Human rights, (2 folders)
    - "H" miscellaneous (Box II:789)
    - Immigration
    - Iraq, (4 folders)
    - "I-J" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy family, (2 folders)
    - Kissinger, Henry, (1 folder) (Box II:790)
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Law, (2 folders)
    - Lester of Herne Hill, Anthony Paul Lester, Baron
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Middle East
      - Americans for Peace Now, Middle East Peace Report
      - General, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box II:791)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times
    - "N-O" miscellaneous
    - Politics
      - General
      - Nader, Ralph
      - Presidential election of 2000, (3 folders) (Box II:792)
    - Presidential Citizens Medal, (2 folders)
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Race, (2 folders)
    - Religion (Box II:793)
    - Right (political and religious conservatism), (2 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Secrecy See also Classified
    - Speeches
      - Jan.-Apr., (7 folders)
      - May-Aug., (5 folders) (Box II:794)
      - Sept. 17-25, (3 folders)
      - Sept. 30, (1 folder) (Box II:795)
      - Oct.-Nov., (3 folders)
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Television (Box II:796)
    - Terrorism
      - Court
      - General
      - Rights, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:797)
    - "T-U" miscellaneous
    - Vietnam, (2 folders)
    - "V-W" miscellaneous
    - Yugoslavia, (3 folders)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
  - 2003 (Box II:798)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - American Law Institute, Philadelphia, Penn.
    - Australia
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Book reviews, (4 folders)
    - Boudin, Kathy
    - Brennan Center for Justice, New York, N.Y.
    - Bush, George W., (2 folders) (Box II:799)
    - Bylines
      - American Prospect
      - Century Foundation, Homeland Security Project, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:800)
      - Felman, Dedi
      - General, (3 folders)
      - Handler, Carole
      - Kincaid, Jamacia
      - The New York Review of Books, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:801)
      - New York Times
      - Schulz, William
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - Capital punishment (Box II:802)
    - Chapultepec Grand Prize
    - Clinton, Bill, Kenneth Starr
    - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - Courts, (2 folders)
    - Crime
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Defense
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Economy
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Fair trail, free press, (1 folder) (Box II:803)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation
    - Free speech
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gideon's Trumpet, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:804)
    - Great Britain
      - General
      - Trip
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard Magazine
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Health
    - Human rights
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Immigration
      - General
      - Synnestvedt, Inga R. (Box II:805)
    - Iraq War
      - General, (4 folders)
      - Law
      - Post war, (2 folders)
      - Weapons of mass destruction
    - Italy
      - General
      - Trip, (3 folders) (Box II:806)
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - Jacobs, Virginia B.
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Middle East
      - Americans For Peace Now
      - General, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:807)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times, (2 folders)
    - "N-O" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Politics
      - Cheney, Richard B.
      - General
    - "P-R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Speeches
      - Jan., (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:808)
      - Feb., (5 folders)
      - March, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:809)
      - Apr.-May, (6 folders)
      - June-Sept., (7 folders) (Box II:810)
      - Oct., (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:811)
      - Nov.-Dec., (7 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Terrorism (Box II:812)
      - General
      - Rights
        - Courts, (2 folders)
        - General, (4 folders)
        - Guantanamo Bay, (1 folder) (Box II:813)
      - Hamdi, Yaser Esam, (2 folders)
      - Padilla, Jose, (4 folders) (Box II:814)
    - "T-W" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Yale Biographical Dictionary of American Law
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
  - 2004
    - Africa
      - South Africa
      - Zimbabwe, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:815)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - Ashcroft, John D.
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Baldwin, Roger N., (2 folders)
    - Book plugs
    - Bush, George W., (2 folders) (Box II:816)
    - Bylines
      - American Prospect
      - Arafat, Yasir
      - Brown v. Board of Education
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Los Angeles Times
      - Mother Jones
      - New York Review of Books, (1 folder) (Box II:817)
      - New York Times
      - O'Donnell, Pierce
      - Torture
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - "C-F" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Gideon v. Wainwright
    - Great Britain
    - "G-H" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:818)
    - Immigration
    - Iraq
      - General, (4 folders)
      - Prisons
    - "I-J" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy family
    - "K-L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Marshall, Margaret H. (wife), (2 folders) (Box II:819)
    - Middle East
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times
    - "N-R" miscellaneous
    - Society of American Historians, New York, N.Y., (2 folders)
    - Speeches
      - Jan.
      - Feb., (4 folders) (Box II:820)
      - Mar. 2-16, (5 folders)
      - Mar. 29 (Box II:821)
      - Apr.-Nov., (9 folders)
      - Dec., (2 folders) (Box II:822)
    - "S" miscellaneous
    - Terrorism
      - General
      - Rights
        - General
        - Guantanamo Bay, (2 folders)
    - Torture, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box II:823)
    - "T-Y" miscellaneous
  - 2005
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - American Philosophical Society (Box II:824)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Book plug
    - Brennan Center for Justice, New York, N.Y.
    - Bylines
      - American Bar Association report
      - Bybee, Keith J.
      - Chasanow, Abram
      - General
      - In Time of War
      - The Judges Journal
      - The Nation, (3 folders)
      - The New York Review of Books
        - Abrams, Floyd
        - General
      - New York Times, (3 folders) (Box II:825)
      - The Torture Papers: The Road to Abu Ghrab
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - Constitution
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Courts
    - "C-E" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Free speech, (1 folder) (Box II:826)
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Germany
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - Great Britain
      - Laws
      - Trip
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Human rights
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Immigration
    - International Criminal Court, (2 folders)
    - Iraq, (2 folders) (Box II:827)
    - Italy
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Middle East
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Politics
    - Powell, Colin L., (2 folders)
    - "P-Q" miscellaneous
    - Radack, Jesselyn
    - Religion
    - Russia (Box II:828)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Schiavo, Terri
    - Speeches
      - Jan., (2 folders)
      - Feb., (2 folders)
      - Mar.
      - Apr., (2 folders) (Box II:829)
      - May-Sept., (6 folders)
      - Oct., (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:830)
      - Nov.-Dec., (3 folders)
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous
    - Television
    - Terrorism
      - General
      - Rights
        - General
        - Guantanamo Bay, (3 folders) (Box II:831)
        - Padilla, Jose, (3 folders)
        - Patriot Act, (2 folders)
    - Torture, (1 folder); (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box II:832, Box II:833)
    - "T-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 2006
    - Afghanistan
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Book plugs
    - Bush, George W.
    - Bylines
      - First Amendment Center, Washington, D.C., (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:834)
      - General
      - New York Review of Books, (3 folders)
      - New York Times
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - "C-E" miscellaneous (Box II:835)
    - Freund, Paul A.
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gonzales, Alberto R.
    - Great Britain, (2 folders)
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Immigration
    - Iraq, (2 folders)
    - "I-L" miscellaneous (Box II:836)
    - Middle East, (2 folders)
    - Miller, Judith
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - National Security Agency, (2 folders)
    - New York Times
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Race
    - Right (political conservatism)
    - Rumsfeld, Donald
    - "R" miscellaneous (Box II:837)
    - Secrecy
    - Speeches
      - Jan.-Sept., (8 folders)
      - Oct. 4-5
      - Oct. 21-25, (3 folders) (Box II:838)
      - Nov.
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous
    - Terrorism
      - General
      - Rights
        - General
        - Guantanamo Bay See also Classified, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:839)
        - Hamdi, Yaser Esam, (2 folders)
        - Padilla, Jose
    - Torture, (5 folders)
    - "T-Y" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:840)
  - 2007
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, (2 folders)
    - American Philosophical Society, (2 folders)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Birthday
    - Book plugs, (2 folders)
    - Bush, George W.
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - Central Intelligence Agency, (2 folders) (Box II:841)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists
    - Courts
    - "D-E" miscellaneous
    - Free speech
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - Gonzales, Alberto R.
    - Great Britain
      - General
      - Law
      - Trip
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Immigration (Box II:842)
    - Iran
    - Iraq
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy, John F, and Robert F.Kennedy
    - Kissinger, Henry
    - "K-L" miscellaneous
    - Middle East
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times
    - Nieman Foundation
    - "N-S" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Terrorism
      - General
      - Rights
        - General
        - Guantanamo Bay, (3 folders) (Box II:843)
    - Torture, (3 folders)
    - "T-Z" miscellaneous
- Part II: Letters from Readers, 1957-2001 (Box II:843-940)
  Letters from readers of Lewis's columns, usually accompanied by his replies.
  Arranged chronologically by year and therein alphabetically by name of person or topic. Filed at the end of each year are letters to the editor about Lewis's columns.
  - 1957-1972, (5 folders) (Box II:843)
  - 1975 (Box II:844)
    - "A-E" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - "F-L" miscellaneous", (8 folders) (Box II:845)
    - "M-R" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box II:846)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:847)
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - United Nations resolution
    - "U-Z" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1976 (Box II:848)
    - "A-H" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Irish Republican Army, (2 folders) (Box II:849)
    - Italy
    - "I-N" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - "O-Z" miscellaneous, (10 folders) (Box II:850)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1977
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - "B-J" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box II:851)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:852)
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Middle East, (3 folders)
    - "M-Q" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Race relations
    - "R-Z" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box II:853)
    - Letters to the editor
    - Selected letters and columns, 1977-1980
  - 1978
    - "A-C" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "D-E" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:854)
    - Farber, Myron, case
    - "F-L" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Middle East, (6 folders); (12 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:855, Box II:856)